TUSHAR SINGHANIYA

Location: Noida, UP 201301 | Mobile: +91-7055055999 | Email: tusharsinghaniya@gmail.com

Web: https://www.tusharsinghaniya.com | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tusharsinghaniya/

GitHub: https://github.com/tusharsinghaniya/

SENIOR PRODUCT MANAGER | PROGRAM MANAGER

Product Management | Program Management | Agile | Strategy | Digital Transformation

Customer obsessed and value driven professional with 10.5+ years of experience leading cross functional teams, through software development lifecycle, utilizing design thinking to deliver both customers facing and enterprise grade products. Strategy leader in the area of product and program management, including data driven decision, vision, roadmap, stakeholder management, team leadership, transformation, market research and launch. Led teams of 20-150 people across technology, business and design departments and responsible for \$10M+ budgets.

QUALIFICATIONS SUMMARY

| Business | Product Management, Program Management, SaaS/Enterprise Software, Customer Interview, Business Analysis, Business Intelligence, Process Automation |
|----------|--|
| Software | Jira, Trello, HP ALM, BMC Remedy, MS Project, MS Visio, Balsamiq, Whimsical, Marvel, |
| | Tableau, Power Bl |
| Design | Enterprise Design Thinking, User Experience (UX) Design, User Interface Design, Product |
| | Design, A/B Testing |
| Strategy | Cross Functional Team Lead, Agile (Scrum, Kanban, SAFe), Product Roadmap, Product |
| | Vision, Product Release, Product Launch, Prioritization, Software Development |
| | Lifecycle, Stakeholder Management, Vendor Management, People Management, |
| | Performance Management, Marketing, Pricing, Growth and Strategic Planning |
| | |

EXPERIENCE

Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) Senior Product Manager

May 2016 to Present

- Spearheaded pharmacy management product execution from inception to launch, enabling Rx/drug dispensing of 40+ million prescriptions per year on 9000+ stores.
- Introduced agile ways of working and implemented SAFe framework in IT portfolio of 1000+ associates resulting in productivity increase by 18%.
- Established B2B wholesale partner channel enabling supply chain operations in international portfolio and achieved revenue gain of 10% QoQ.
- Led cross functional teams and implemented largest SAP S/4 Hana replacing legacy AS400 systems on 8500+ stores resulted in \$50 million/year reduction of license fees and operational costs.
- Designed store price batching capability for PCMS's POS product which enabled PCMS organization to comply with legal compliance and enter \$15 billion US retail POS market.
- Eliminated waste through automation of 40+ key reports, tasks and business processes and saved \$1.2 million annually.

- **Product Manager**
- Identified opportunity and designed centralized retail pricing process for 8000+ stores and managed entire product lifecycle, resulted in \$20 million EBIT benefits and 30% increase in business efficiency.
- Conceptualized "Deployment Dashboard" with capability of deploying product features on 8000+ stores and producing KPIs and customer success metrics.
- Implemented suite of web/mobile apps providing 12000+ users with ability to setup, optimize, manage and execute retail pricing.
- Created consensus among 12+ stakeholder groups across the organization and external vendors on product vision, release map and product roadmap, thus achieving 100% customer satisfaction.
- Led user interviews, research with end users and user personas, customer feedback and behaviour and gathered key stakeholder pain points to define business case, product backlog and MVP.

Tata Consultancy Services (TCS) Product Lead

December 2010 to January 2013

- Collaborated with 10+ teams and improved customer satisfaction to 100% by meeting IT Operations SLAs such as on-time delivery, defect density, MTTR and ageing
- Performed root cause identification, analysis, pareto analysis and defect elimination in master data portfolio, thus reduced MTTR (Mean Time Taken for Resolution) from 3.8 days to 2.2 days.
- Handled team of 30 associates and executed IT operations in managed-services model which included application support of 20+ business applications with varied technical stack.

AWARDS AND HONORS

- **Certificate of Merit from CBSE** Award for outstanding academic performance and among top 0.1% of successful candidates of all India secondary school examinations 2004 in IT.
- **Best Case Study Award** Award from TCS Technology Excellence Group, for being in top three out of 1285 entries in most complex implementation category.
- ILP Top Performer Award Award from TCS for being in top 10 trainees out of 1000+ trainees for outstanding performance in "Initial Learning Program".
- **Certificate of Excellence from Vividha Academy** Selected in 16 players squad out of 700 players in summer camp to represent academy and compete at state and national level matches.

EDUCATION

MBA | Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Kozhikode | 2020 - 2022

B. Tech, Computer Science | Uttar Pradesh Technical University (UPTU), Lucknow | 2006 – 2010

PROFESSIONAL COURSES

Certificate, Digital Product Management | Darden School of Business, University of Virginia
Certificate, Business Analytics | Wharton Online, University of Pennsylvania
Certificate, Business Strategy | Darden School of Business, University of Virginia
Certificate, Business Strategies for a Better World | Wharton Online, University of Pennsylvania
Certificate, Marketing Strategy | IE Business School
Certificate, Marketing Mix | IE Business School

Certificate, Leading Modern Day Business | Darden School of Business, University of Virginia Certificate, Entrepreneurship: Launching an Innovative Business | University of Maryland Certificate, Executive Data Science | The Johns Hopkins University Certificate, Business Technology Management | Indian School of Business (ISB) Certificate, New Product Development | Indian Institute of Management (IIM), Bangalore Certificate, Omnichannel Retail Strategy | Wharton Online, University of Pennsylvania Diploma, Business Analysis (Specialization – Retail Domain) | TCS Business Domain Academy

PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

- Project Management Professional (PMP®)
- Google Project Management
- PRINCE2® Practitioner
- Lean Six Sigma Green Belt
- Professional Scrum Master (PSM I)
- SAFe Practitioner
- Tableau Desktop Specialist
- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals
- IBM Enterprise Design Thinking Practitioner
- Brand and Product Management

- Agile Certified Practitioner (PMI-ACP®)
- Google UX Design
- ITIL[®] Foundation
- RPA Program Manager
- Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO I)
- Kanban Foundation KIKF®
- Microsoft Data Analyst Associate
- Atlassian Jira Essentials
- Product Analytics Certification (PAC)
- BCG Leading Modern-Day Business